☐ (+1) 814-777-7019 | **I**f3ixiao@gmail.com | **f**fxiao.me | **D**xiaofen9 | **D**f-xiao

Summary _

I am a machine learning researcher working at Palo Alto Networks. Prior to that, I earned CS Ph.D. from Georgia Tech, where I conducted research in machine learning (ML) and systems security&privacy. Published 5+ first-author research works at top-tier conferences including IEEE S&P, USENIX SEC, BlackHat USA, etc. Member of Program Committees at premium AI conferences including ACM WWW.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2023

- Worked on Software security and machine learning with Prof. Wenke Lee.
- GPA: 3.9/4

Wuhan University Wuhan, China

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Sept. 2014 - Jun. 2018

• GPA: 3.87/4

Work Experience _____

Palo Alto Networks CA, USA

SENIOR STAFF RESEARCHER

Dec 2023 - Now

- Leading the development of Transformer-based representation learning for text-based malware analysis, contributing 10% detection improvement for previous false negatives.
- Developing and optimizing large-scale data pipeline (with BigQuery) for ML feature selection and generation, reducing data processing over-head from hours to minutes.
- Developing algorithms for tracking and explaining concept drifting in ML pipelines, addressing out-of-distribution and adversarial sample challenges.
- Techniques: Language Models, Online learning, Machine learning model serving, SQL for data processing pipeline

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

May. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Designed and implemented the Tsunami Callback Service, which enables Google Cloud Vulnerability Scanner to detect log4j-like vulnerabilities.
 My work is now open-sourced and actively maintained by Google https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner-callback-server
- · Leveraged CI/CD techniques in Google to launch my project in production environments (early launch, exceeding expectation).
- Gave two tech talks at Google. I shared my previous research works on web vulnerability analysis.
- · Techniques: Java, Distributed Systems, Low-latency System Design, OWASP Vulnerability Assessment, Kubernetes.

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Made fundamental changes to the Linux virtual memory management system to enable fast I/O for Confidential VMs at Google Cloud.
- Improved Confidential VM network throughput by 20%.
- · Identified a potentially serious bug in our product and received a Google Peer Bonus Award.
- Techniques: C&C++, Linux Memory Management, Linux I/O Internals, Cloud Virtualization, AMD SEV, Confidential Computing.

Publication _____

5 FIRST-AUTHOR WORKS IN TOP-TIER CONFERENCES

FaceObfuscator: Defending Deep Learning-based Privacy Attacks with Gradient Descent-Resistant Features in Face Recognition.

USENIX SEC'24

Shuaifan Jin, He Wang, Zhibo Wang, **Feng Xiao**, Jiahui Hu, Yuan He, Wenwen Zhang, Zhongjie Ba, Weijie Fang, Shuhong Yuan, Kui Ren

JASMINE: Scale up JavaScript Static Security Analysis with Computation-based Semantic Explanation.

IEEE S&P'24

FENG XIAO, ZHONGFU SU GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

May 23, 2024 Feng Xiao · Résumé

WEBRR: A Forensic System for Replaying and Investigating Web-Based Attacks in The Modern Web

USENIX SEC'24

JOEY ALLEN, ZHENG YANG, FENG XIAO, MATTHEW LANDEN, ROBERTO PERDISCI, WENKE LEE

Understanding and Mitigating Remote Code Execution Vulnerabilities in Cross-Platform Ecosystem.

ACM CCS'22

FENG XIAO, IAN ZHENG, JOEY ALLEN, GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

Abusing Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

USENIX Security'21

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Discovering Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

BlackHat'20

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Unexpected Data Dependency Creation and Chaining: A New Attack to SDN.

IEEE S&P'20

FENG XIAO, JINQUAN ZHANG, JIANWEI HUANG, GUOFEI GU, DINGHAO WU, PENG LIU

PatternListener: Cracking Android Pattern Lock Using Acoustic Signals.

ACM CCS'18

 ${\sf Man\,Zhou,\,Qian\,Wang,\,Jingxiao\,Yang,\,Qi\,Li,\,\textbf{Feng\,Xiao},\,Zhibo\,Wang,\,Xiaofeng\,Chen.}$

Hacking the Brain: Customize Evil Protocol to Pwn an SDN Controller.

DEFCON'18

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, PENG LIU.

Enabling Secure Location Authentication in Drone (poster).

ACM MobiCom'17

FENG XIAO, MAN ZHOU, YOUCHENG LIYE, JINGXIAO YANG, QIAN WANG.

Honors____

2021	Most Innovative Research Runner-up	Pwnie Award, USA
2019	Chair Fellowship.	Atlanta, USA
2018	Rednor IST Fellowship.	State College, USA
2018	ACM CCS Student Travel Grant Award.	Toronto, Canada
2017	LeiJun Scholarship (Top 1 out of 310).	Wuhan, China
2016	National Scholarship (Awarded to top 0.2% undergrads nationwide)	Wuhan, China
2015	Yuanyi Scholarship.	Wuhan, China

Programming languages _____

Natively fluent: Java, Python, Node.js

Conversationally fluent: C, PHP, Matlab